A Guide to the Charles James Apperley [Nimrod] Papers 1797-1851
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Volume Three 1824-1825, ca. 84 items mounted on 75 pages
  Colonel [Henry?] Wyndham page 32
  Mr. Wynne & his marriage to "a rich widow" page 25
  William Young page 1
  VOLUME FOUR
- Volume Four ca. 1825-1826, ca. 66 items mounted on 62 pages
  Volume four of the Nimrod letters, ca. 1825-1826, consists of ca. 66 items mounted on 62 pages. Apperley writes about his relationship with Pittman, "I cannot conceive what you allude to in 'the tone of my letter.' I am not aware of having said anything that could have hurt your feelings - on the contrary, all I say, do, or think of, is for our mutual interest" (page 3, [1825]). Apperley also assures him, "All my predictions will be verified and in another year or so, The Sporting Magazine will be one of the most interesting periodical works going, and its circulation unbounded"(page 6). He reports to Pittman, "the whole county rings with the praises of Nimrod's second Tour. I told you how it would be!" (page 19, [1826] Mar 5). Elsewhere Nimrod writes, "Indeed, from the beginning to the end, the work is worthy of the title it bears, and I assure you I feel an honest pride in the reflection that I have been so powerful and instrument in advancing it to its present respectability" (page 51, [1826]). Apperley discusses his financial difficulties, "Had these difficulties been brought on me by extravagant living, or any other misconduct, I could not hold this language to you; but this has not been the case. I have barely allowed myself the necessaries of life, and have been guilty of no extravagance. My debts have been contracted by my connection with your work" (page 58, [1826?]).
  Articles mentioned in volume 4 as sent or in preparation:
  "Condition of Hunters" pages 7, 9, 33, 34
  "Last Words from a Loser" page 61
  "Pembrokeshire Hunt" (not by Apperley) page 10
  preservation of game and the destruction of foxes page 3
  "Riding to Hounds" pages 2, 9
  "The Road" pages 11, 31, 32, 33, 36, 43, 57
  "The Tour" pages 19, 20, 27, 30, 52
  Subjects mentioned in volume 4:
  Apperley asks Pittman for a release from his contract & other negotiations pages 5, 58, 59
  Apperley's expense account for the Tour page 4
  Apperley's farm & horses pages 2, 5, 11, 31, 32, 40, 55, 56, 62
  Apperley's financial difficulties pages 2, 5, 13, 16, 18, 19, 27, 30, 31, 33, 52, 53, 55, 58, 59, 62
  Apperley's plan for future articles page 5
  Colonel Berkeley page 3, 17
  Mr. Biddulph page 12
  Cheshire fox hounds page 16
  Marquis of Cleveland page 53
  [Norton Conyers?] pages 46, 48
  coursing meeting pages 41, 49
  Lord Darlington pages 42, 43, 44, 48, 49, 51
  Lord Derby's hunt page 2
  John James Farquharson page 35
  hounds visited by Apperley, list of page 45
  Mr. Gifford page 43
  Duke of Grafton page 23
  Sir Bellingham Graham pages 5, 10, 16, 26, 31, 41, 42, 43
  Mr. Holloway page 43
  [John] Horlock page 51
  Lord Kennedy page 19
  Ralph Lambton pages 38, 44
  Mr. Lawrence pages 47, 51
  Leicestershire page 9
  John Lockley pages 3, 7, 8, 27
  Mr. Lucy (descendant of Justice Shallow) pages 3, 36
  Lord [Lynedocks?] pages 22, 23
  Sir Harry Mainwaring, letter from page 16
  Mr. [George?] Marriott page 10
  C. Mathews pages 36, 37
  Mr. Milbanke page 42
  [John] Musters page 21
  John Mytton pages 15, 21, 27
  Mr. Nicoll pages 11, 12
  Nim North page 41
  North Devon stag hounds page 1
  "the Old Forester" pages 31, 50, 51
  George Osbaldeston page 28
  Philip Payne pages 21, 39, 43, 49, 51
  Lord Portsmouth page 53
  Sir Richard Puleston pages 9, 15, 27
  Raby Hunt Club page 44
  Captain Ross pages 19, 24, 25
  saddle, self-adjusting page 27
  Shamrock (the horse) pages 40, 44, 45, 47
  the great Tom Smith, new wife, & his fox hounds pages 51, 53
  Sir Tatton Sykes page 43
  Lord Tavistock page 23
  John Warde & his dog Comfort pages 7, 8, 11, 12, 51
  Captain Warrington page 60
  Mr. West of Alscot Park pages 3, 40
  Matty Wilkinson pages 44, 46
  Reginald Winniatt page 3
  Yorkshire Tour & Apperley's expenses pages 47, 50, 57
  VOLUME FIVE
- Volume Five ca. 1826-1828, 102 items mounted on 76 pages
  Volume five of the Nimrod letters, ca. 1826-1828, consists of 102 items mounted 76 pages. In this volume his financial difficulties and complaints continue, "Whatever my future fate may be, I shall have this to console me - I have exerted myself to the utmost- nay indeed, to the manifest injury to my health for the well-doing of the magazine and I have done what no other person could have done for its advancement. I may say still more that nothing but a personal regard for yourself would have, under existing circumstances, kept me to the collar as long as I have been at it" (page 1, 1827 Jan). He continues, "Altercation you say is unnecessary and I see no reason for it. The world will of course know what has [dissolved?] our contract, and I think it will say there was nothing unreasonable in my demand, which would give me a year to endeavor to write myself out of debt, and the produce of my pen to go to the Magazine. If I am to work hard, and get poorer every year, it shall not be my fault if I don't try to remedy the evil" (page 23, 1827 June 30).
  Articles mentioned in volume 5 as sent or in preparation:
  Acton Fair page 31
  the biography of Buckle page 45
  "Condition of Hunters" pages 5, 6, 9, 49, 64, 74
  dandyism page 75
  "Feast of Wit" pages 57, 64
  fishing pages 57, 64, 66
  India sporting article page 54
  ornithology page 14
  "The Road" pages 21, 37, 46, 51, 57, 66, 70, 74, 75
  Surrey hounds pages 42, 47
  "The Tour" pages 2, 11, 15, 24, 27, 31, 32, 34, 37, 39, 46, 60, 70
  Subjects mentioned in volume 5:
  Abingdon Race page 51
  advertisement by Apperley for his "Condition of Hunters" page 49
  Apperley asks Pittman for a release from his contract & other negotiations pages 1, 5, 10, 23, 29, 35, 47, 71
  Apperley suffering from eye inflammation page 18
  Apperley's farm & horses pages 3, 5, 9, 11, 13, 19, 34, 36, 41, 42, 51, 68, 73, 76
  Apperley's financial difficulties pages 1, 3, 5, 6, 7, 10, 11, 17, 19, 21, 23, 25, 26, 28, 29, 30, 32, 33, 36, 38, 40, 43, 44, 47, 48, 54, 55, 56, 61, 62, 63, 68, 71
  Duke of Beaufort page 76
  Berkeley staghounds page 14, 58
  Mr. Biddulf page 11, 57
  Sir H. Carew page 67
  Chester Races pages 50, 73
  [Harvey?] Combe page 76
  Sir John Cope page 2
  Vincent Corbet & [Darius?] pages 6, 18
  Sir Vincent Cotton page 33
  Lord Darlington pages 4, 52
  Sir John Dashwood pages 24, 35, 38, 63
  Lord Derby page 45
  John James Farquharson pages 50, 60
  Glenartney (the horse) & the Derby page 22
  Sir Harry Goodricke page 17
  Duke of Grafton page 8
  Sir Bellingham Graham pages 1, 74
  Lord Harewood page 4
  Frederick Heysham page 76
  hunting counties, possible article re page 47
  Lord Jersey page 22
  Colonel Jolliffe page 45
  Mr. Lawrence pages 27, 28, 53
  John Lockley pages 46, 69, 76
  Lord [Lynedocks?] pages 16, 73
  Lord [MacDonald?] page 3
  [John] Musters page 8
  Nim North page 37
  George Osbaldeston pages 8, 15
  Paris races, an account of, by Strickland page 7
  Philip Payne pages 8, 37, 73
  Lord Portsmouth page 34
  Sir Richard Puleston page 65
  Raby Hunt Club pages 3, 4
  Mr. Ramsey, the painter, page 46
  riding to hounds, expertise of Apperley page 47
  Captain Ross page 39
  Duke of Rutland page 47
  Shamrock (the horse) page 11
  Mr. Shaw pages 45, 46
  Mr. Strickland pages 7, 44, 70, 74
  Mr. [George?] Templer page 67
  Mr. West page 14
  W. Wynn page 59
  VOLUME SIX
- Volume Six ca. 1824-1828, 83 items mounted on 79 pages
  Volume six contains letters from Apperley, most following the death of John Pittman, ca. 1824-1828, 83 items mounted on 79 pages, chiefly to and from Mr. Henry Crawter, the executor of Pittman's estate and representative for Mrs. Mary Ann Pittman in her dealings with Apperley, and including several letters to William Young and D.N. Shuey. In a letter to Crawter, Apperley writes, "I have always been a great admirer of women in certain situations and places but in the way of business I abhor them. They are, for the most part, suspicious, illiberal, and see no further than the present moment; so that on the present occasion I must look to you to arrange matters in Warwick Square" (page 2, 1827 Dec 21). To the editor of The Sporting Magazine, William Young, Apperley threatens to quit, "I am quite prepared for consequences, and having lost the tie that has hitherto bound me to the task - I mean a strong personal regard for Pittman - I care not how soon I quit an occupation that has never put a shilling into my pocket, but has fixed me with the charge of taking it out of that of others" (page 10, 1828 Jan [28?]). Nimrod also observes, "I understand when Mrs. P. speaks of me - It is that fellow" (page 13, [1828 Jan]). For another letter mentioning his relationship with Mrs. Mary Ann Pittman see page 53, July 7, 1828.
  The draft of Apperley's "advertisement" concerning his retirement from The Sporting Magazine reads as follows, "Never having had much relish for Hampshire hunting, and being unable to afford to go from home for better, I have determined on retiring from the field. Under such circumstances, it would be presumptuous in me to continue to write in The Sporting Magazine under the imposing signature of Nimrod. I therefore think it proper to state, that nothing in that work in future will proceed from my pen, with the exception of two more letters, concluding the Yorkshire Tour which shall appear at my earliest convenience" (page 15, 1828 Jan 31).
  Articles mentioned in volume 6 as sent or in preparation:
  "Condition of Hunters" pages 43, 47, 49, 57, 62, 75
  game laws page 43
  "The Road" pages 43, 62
  "The Tour" pages 5, 8, 28, 29, 30, 32, 36, 37, 75
  "Ten [Lives?] page 8
  Subjects mentioned in volume 6:
  Apperley's threat to break his contract with The Sporting Magazine and other negotiations pages 6, 10, 11, 12, 13, 16, 18, 20, 21, 22, 23, 24, 30, 33, 34, 53, 59
  Apperley's financial difficulties pages 13, 16, 20, 21, 40-42, 51, 57, 59, 66, 70-74
  Apperley offers himself as editor of The Sporting Magazine if Young retires pages 31, 55, 61
  Mr. [Richard?] Best pages 6, 43
  Lord Cleveland page 33
  Vincent Corbet page 52
  Baron De Biel pages 49, 51, 54
  Germany, Apperley's trip to pages 53, 54, 55, 65, 67, 68, 70, 76-77
  Mr. Murray pages 15, 21, 25, 30, 32, 33, 43, 45
  "the Old Forester" page 7
  Mrs. Mary Ann Pittman, Apperley's complaints about, pages 53-59, 62, 75-78
  John Pittman, death of page 10
  Mr. West page 52
  Letters to and from Henry Crawter, London:
  Pages 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 7, 9, 11, 12, 13, 14,15, 16, 17, 19, 20, 21-40, 43, 45, 47, 49, 50-66, 69, 70-78
  Letters to Mr. Shuey
  Pages 8, 67
  Letters to editor William Young, Warwick Square, London:
  Pages 6, 10
  VOLUME SEVEN
- Volume Seven 1828-1831, 101 letters mounted on 94 pages
  Volume seven consists of 10l letters mounted on 94 pages, ca. 1828-1831. Apperley continues to complain about The Sporting Magazine and threatens to sever his ties with the magazine, "Circumstances have occurred to render it impossible that as a gentleman and a sportsman, I can continue my contributions to the Sp. Mag. under the signature Nimrod" (page 2, 1828 Oct [8]) and "I have run my eye over the last double number and cannot help observing that with two or three exceptions, such low life trash was never foisted on the public. I shall really feel happy when my name and reputation as a writer is withdrawn from this work" (page 12, 1828 Dec 8).
  Articles mentioned in volume 7 as sent or in preparation:
  "Condition of Hunters" pages 19, 26, 36, 47, 53, 73, 75
  Melton article page 32
  Mervinia article page 47
  "Remarks on Foxhunting" page 47
  "Riding to Hounds" page 59
  Warwickshire article page 59
  Subjects mentioned in volume 7:
  The American Sporting Magazine page 8
  Apperley's farm pages 2, 23, 47
  Apperley's threat to break his contract with The Sporting Magazine and other negotiations pages 2, 3, 6, 7, 8, 9, 11, 24, 25, 28, 29, 32, 38, 44, 61, 62, 63, 65, 66, 69, 72, 75, 77, 85, 87, 88, 89, 90, 91, 92, 94
  Apperley's financial difficulties pages 34, 35, 36, 37, 38, 41
  Calais, France, Apperley's escape to page 83
  Sir John Cope page 47
  Sir John Dashwood page 19
  Baron De Biel page 23
  Newton Fellows page 47
  German Tour pages 4, 7, 10, 13, 14, 23, 25, 29, 39, 51, 73
  [Ragnon ?] Jones page 47
  Mr. Lawrence pages 17, 47
  Mr. Murray page 38, 44
  Mr. Nicoll page 35
  Duke of Orleans, offer to hunt at Chantilly page 43
  Mrs. Mary Ann Pittman, Apperley's complaints about, pages 1, 4, 6, 7, 11, 28, 29, 30, 31, 32, 33, 38, 41, 44, 54, 55, 57, 58, 61, 62, 63, 66, 69, 84, 87, 88, 94
  The Quarterly Review, offer of 1,000 pounds to release Apperley from his contract page 84
  Lord (George Pitt Baron) Rivers, death of page 47
  Letters to John Chandler:
  Pages 22, 39, 40, 46, 50, 80
  Letters to and from Vincent Corbet:
  Pages 15, 16, 17
  Pages 1, 4, 5, 6, 7, 10, 13, 16, 17, 19, 20, 21, 22, 23, 26, 29, 30, 33, 34, 35, 36, 37, 38, 41, 42, 43, 44, 48, 49, 51, 52, 54, 55, 57, 58, 61, 71, 72, 73, 74, 85, 86, 87, 88, 89, 90, 91, 92, 93, 94
  Letters to D.N. Shuey:
  Pages 11, 12, 25, 27, 28, 31, 32
  Letters to Thomas Tibbutt:
  Pages 56, 60, 62, 63, 64, 65, 66, 67, 68, 69, 70, 75, 76, 77, 78, 79, 80, 81, 82, 83
  Pages 11
  VOLUME EIGHT
- Volume Eight 1824-1831, 1849-1851, 159 items mounted on 103 pages
  Volume eight consists of 159 items mounted on 103 pages, ca. 1824-1831 and 1849-1851, including the correspondence of Mrs. Mary Ann Pittman and the staff of The Sporting Magazine, receipts, accounts with contributors to the magazine and with subscribers, and legal documents pertaining to lawsuits, chiefly reflecting the efforts of Mrs. Mary Ann Pittman and her representatives to settle her husband's estate and put her financial affairs on a firmer footing.
  Subjects mentioned in volume 8:
  Apperley's accounts pages 26, 98, 99, 100, 101
  Apperley's contract & other negotiations pages 3, 7, 27, 28, 43
  Apperley's financial demands pages 4, 10, 11
  Brighton Harriers page 22
  The County Herald advertising pages 44, 45, 94
  coursing page 14
  German Tour pages 12, 16, 19, 20, 21
  Mr. Lawrence pages 7, 20
  lawsuit against George Doubell pages 36, 37, 38, 40, 41, 42, 51, 54, 55, 56, 57, 58, 62, 63, 73
  lawsuit against Mr. [Graham] pages 52, 55, 59
  lawsuit against William Heckford pages 31, 32, 33, 34, 49, 53, 60, 61, 69, 71
  lawsuit against Mr. Langdon page 35
  lawsuit against Mr. Martin page 65
  Letters on Condition, possible publication of page 24
  London militia & Lord [Sidmouth's?] letter page 29
  Masters of the Hounds, a list of those contributing financially to Nimrod page 39
  property tax pages 2, 87
  receipts of John & Mary Ann Pittman pages 1, 9, 74-92
  Thomas Tibbutt's account with Mrs. Mary Ann Pittman pages 66, 67, 68
  Correspondents writing to Mrs. Mary Ann Pittman (and earlier letters to Mr. Pittman) in volume 8:
  Charles J. Apperley pages 10, 11, 12
  James Aubrey to Thomas Tibbutt page 64
  Henry Crawter pages 4, 5, 6
  James Robinson page 48
  R. Surridge page 13
  Robert Smith Surtees (1803-1864)["Nim South"] page 22
  Mr. Tattersall pages 25, 72
  [William?] Thacker page 14
  J. Warren page 15
  John Wheble page 47
  Matt Winter page 48
  Copies of correspondence by John Chandler & D.N. Shuey on behalf of Mrs. Mary Ann Pittman:
  Pages 17, 18, 19, 20
  Copies of correspondence by John Chandler & D.N. Shuey on behalf of Mrs. Mary Ann Pittman to Charles J. Apperley:
  Pages 18, 19, 20, 21
  VOLUME NINE
- Volume Nine ca. 1822-1830, 116 items mounted on 97 pages
  Volume nine consists of 116 items mounted on 97 pages, ca. 1822-1830, including correspondence, accounts, receipts, and legal documents concerning the settlement of the John Pittman estate, the business of The Sporting Magazine, and questions concerning the contract and the employment of C.J. Apperley. The rupture in relations between Mrs. Mary Ann Pittman's representative and the executor of the estate, Henry Crawter, and Apperley is shown in his letter of October 6, 1831 (page 18), "All your spouting about the Magazine a fraud on the public is not worth answering. Your last letter to me was a most insulting one and this a tissue of misrepresentation which I flatly say is not true and when insulted you will find I can kick. I must now say I do not intend to waste my time in again writing answers to your misrepresentations and repeat what I said in my last that your threats and daring I hold in sovereign contempt." For additional letters from Crawter to Apperley about their disagreements over his contract and payments see the pages listed below under Crawter's name.
  Subjects mentioned in volume 9:
  Rudolf Ackermann page 64
  Apperley's debts and contract pages 1, 22, 23, 35, 40, 68, 74, 75, 77-81, 9
  Brighton Hurdle Race card page 96
  Mr. Dundas and his stud Rubens page 28
  Edinburgh races page 2
  Pierce Egan (1772-1849) page 62
  German Tour pages 8, 13, 23, 27, 38
  life insurance on C.J. Apperley page 41, 55
  William Miller account page 85
  John Murray page 83, 84
  promissory notes from Apperley pages 45, 46, 53, 59
  "Reminiscences of an English Foxhunter Abroad" by R.S. Surtees page 91
  "The Road" page 72
  Shamrock (a horse) page 20
  The Sporting Magazine, index proposal pages 70, 71
  Frederick Villebois page 28
  John Warde page 28
  Colonel Henry Wyndham page 94
  Correspondents in volume 9:
  George Acker to C.J. Apperley page 48
  C.J. Apperley to John Chandler page 15
  C.J. Apperley to Henry Crawter page 95
  C.J. Apperley to [John Pittman] pages 28, 66, 72, 94
  C.J. Apperley to Thomas Tibbutt page 66
  C.O. Apperley (son) to C.J. Apperley page 64
  Charles George Belt to Henry Crawter page 4
  George Biggs to C.J. Apperley page 62
  Mr. Boland to Mrs. Mary Ann Pittman page 90
  B. Brown to C.J. Apperley page 34
  Mr. Vincent Corbet to Henry Crawter pages 24, 25, 27
  Mr. Vincent Corbet to John Pittman page 3
  Henry Crawter to C.J. Apperley pages 15, 18, 19, 29, 31, 32, 33
  Henry Crawter to [V. Corbet] pages 22, 23, 26
  Henry Crawter to Mrs. Mary Ann Pittman page 17
  Henry Crawter to Mr. Tattersall pages 16, 30
  Henry Crawter to Thomas Tibbutt page 17
  Henry Crawter to agents for money owed to the John Pittman estate pages 5, 14
  Rev. [William Barker?] Daniel (1753-1833) to John Pittman pages 70-71
  George Glover to Henry Crawter page 1
  Sir Bellingham Graham to C.J. Apperley page 54
  Mr. Holloway to C.J. Apperley pages 42, 67
  "Jacques" to the Editors of The Sporting Magazine page 92
  John Murray to C.J. Apperley page 50
  John [Norwood?] to C.J. Apperley page 52
  Lord Palmerston [Henry John Temple] page 74
  William Percivall to C.J. Apperley page 49
  John Pittman to C.J. Apperley pages 36-37, 75, 77-82, 84, 88
  John Pittman to [Charles] George Belt page 76
  Quarterly Review editor, [H.L.?] to C.J. Apperley page 83
  Samuel Reynolds to C.J. Apperley page 44
  Letter to Rev. John Russell re getting introduction to Nimrod for writer's son page 86
  Rev. John Russell to C.J. Apperley page 47
  R. Sanders to C.J. Apperley pages 56, 60, 63, 65
  D.N. Shuey to C.J. Apperley page 2
  Robert Smith Surtees (1803-1864) to D.N. Shuey page 91
  Mr. Tattersall to C.J. Apperley page 11
  Mr. Tattersall to Henry Crawter pages 8, 9, 10, 12, 13
  Mr. Tattersall to D.N. Shuey page 89
  Thomas Tibbutt to C.J. Apperley page 39
  Thomas Tibbutt to Mr. Tattersall page 73
  Mr. Young to Mr. Tattersall page 13
  Mr. West to C.J. Apperley page 61
  John Whyte to Henry Crawter page 20-a
  Miscellaneous Letters to Henry Crawter re the John Pittman estate pages 6, 7
  VOLUME TEN
- Volume Ten ca. 1797, 1822-1833, 1847, 71 items mounted on 64 pages
  Volume ten consists of 71 items mounted on 64 pages, ca. 1797, and 1822-1833, and 1847, containing correspondence and manuscripts addressed to the staff of The Sporting Magazine.
  Manuscripts in volume 10:
  "Annual Golfing Match" (1831) page 20
  Arabian Horse article page 41
  "Arrian on Coursing" translated by John Bohn and reviewed by L.L.W. page 50
  "Ayr Western Meeting" (1831) page 19
  "A Bacchanalian Ode" page 44
  "Cricketing" proof sheet page 64
  "Fox Chase Extraordinary" page 57
  "The Ladies Anticipated Grand Equestrian Feat" by "Philo Diana" (proof sheet) page 45
  "The Late Hurdle Race at Brighton" page 39-40
  "Lines Written on the Death of Brush A Favorite Horse in the Berkeley Hunt" [post 1817] page 2
  Melton Mowbray article by "Alfred" pages 46, 47
  "The Orkney Island Bird-Catchers" page 64
  "The Pointer Bitch" by "Halycon" [1797] page 1
  "Reply to the late inquiry on the portrait of Morwick Batt" by "Philo Turf" page 51
  Sepoy article page 38
  "Sporting Fracas" (1831) pages 18, 60-63
  "Sporting Law" (1829) page 12
  Letter answering "Nimrod's mode of Summering the Hunter" by a member of the Burton Hunt (1825 Dec 4) page 13
  Correspondents in volume 10:
  "Agricola" to Editor of The Sporting Magazine page 22
  [C.J. Apperley?] to John Pittman pages 6, 64
  Crawford Archer to Editor of The Sporting Magazine page 64
  W.H. Armstrong to Editor of The Sporting Magazine page 32
  Isaac Barnes to Henry Crawter page 11
  "A Briton" to Editor of The Sporting Magazine page 24
  Sam Chips to Editor of The Sporting Magazine page 36
  [William] Clarke to John Pittman and Editor of The Sporting Magazine pages 3, 4, 59
  "A Constant Reader" to Editor of The Sporting Magazine page 33
  N. Copland to Henry Crawter page 15
  John M. Davies to D.N. Shuey page 27
  "A Foxhunter" to Mary Ann Pittman page 28
  T.R.H. to Editor of The Sporting Magazine page 59
  B. Hart to Editor of The Sporting Magazine page 55
  Christopher Harris to D.N. Shuey page 30
  G. Agar Hausard ("Rusticus") pages 23, 56
  Edward Hickman to Editor of The Sporting Magazine page 25
  Charles Howe to Mary Ann Pittman page 26
  "An Irish Horse Breeder" to Editor of The Sporting Magazine page 37
  "Noon Day" [Mr. Jackson?] page 58
  J. Orton to Editor of The Sporting Magazine page 31, 35
  William Smallwood to Henry Crawter page 5
  [Tobius ?] Smith to Editor of The Sporting Magazine page 34
  William Sullivan Editor of The Sporting Magazine page 18
  [William?] Thacker to John Chandler page 17
  G. Osborne [Townshend] to Editor of The Sporting Magazine page 16
  Charles Trist to Editor of The Sporting Magazine page 48
  "Veterinarius" to Editor of The Sporting Magazine re article "The Veterinary Surgeon" (1827) page 7
  C.W. to Editor of The Sporting Magazine page 9
  John Warren to Mary Ann Pittman page 10
  "The Young Forester" to Mary Ann Pittman page 21
  Subjects in volume 10:
  Matthew Aylett, possible subject for a published portrait page 10
  bear or bull baiting page 52
  Sir John Cope page 15
  The Craven Hunt page 15
  "Dashwood" [N. Copland] pages 15, 49
  John James Farquharson page 49
  German Tour, where is Nimrod's account? page 14
  George Goold page 48
  Lord Kintore page 15
  "The Late Mr. Baird" (see SM 1828 Aug) page 9
  John Mytton, sale of property containing the old race course page 25
  yachting pages 36, 42
  VOLUME ELEVEN
- Volume Eleven 1816-1839, 96 items mounted on 75 pages
  Volume eleven consists of 96 items mounted on 75 pages, ca. 1816-1839, including correspondence by contributors to The Sporting Magazine other than Charles J. Apperley.
  Manuscripts in volume 11:
  "R. Ancell Gun Maker" by "Luck Penny" page 43
  Churches & stained glass windows, letter of opinion for County Herald(1830) page 38
  "New Safety Fowling-Piece" proof sheet page 62
  Correspondents in volume 11:
  Joseph Anderson to Mary Ann Pittman page 51
  C.J. Apperley to John Pittman page 13
  Sir Alexander Bannerman to Editor of The Sporting Magazine page 61